College english test band four
大学英语四级考试
Part two
第二部分
Listening comprehension section a directions , in this section
听力理解 A节 说明：在本节中
You will hear three news reports
你将听到三篇新闻报道
At the end of each news report
每篇新闻报道结束后
You will hear two or three questions
你将听到两到三个问题
Both the news report and the questions will be spoken only once
新闻报道和问题都只读一遍
After you hear a question
听完问题后
You must choose the best answer from the four choices marked a
你必须从标有A的四个选项中选出最佳答案
B , c , and d
B、C和D
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer
然后在答题卡上
Sheet one with a single line through the center
用横线划过相应字母
News report one
新闻报道一
How you noticed how similar you are to your friends
你有没有注意到你和你的朋友有多相似
It may be because your brains operate in harmony with each other
这可能是因为你们的大脑彼此协调运作
We know that friends are more likely to be the same age
我们知道朋友更可能是同龄人
Gender , and ethnic background as each other
相同性别和种族背景
Now it seems that brains are alike , too
现在看来，大脑也很相似
researchers at the university of california
加州大学的研究人员
Scanned the brains of forty two classmates
扫描了四十二名同学的大脑
While i watched videos intended to provoke varying responses
当他们观看旨在引发不同反应的视频时
Some people might find a romantic scene touching , for instance
例如，有些人可能觉得浪漫场景感人
While others would feel it was embarrassing
而其他人会觉得尴尬
The activity of friend's brains was more similar than that of people who didn't know each other
朋友的大脑活动比不认识的人更相似
Particularly in regions involved in attention
特别是在涉及注意力
Emotion , and language
情感和语言的区域
This similarity was strong enough that it could be used to predict
这种相似性足够强，可以用来预测
Whether two people were already friends or not
两个人是否已经是朋友
The relationship probably goes two ways
这种关系可能是双向的
We are drawn to people who think like us
我们被像我们一样思考的人吸引
We then influence their thoughts over time
然后我们随着时间的推移影响他们的思想
Which may push their brain activity into more closely resembling our own
这可能使他们的脑活动更接近我们的
Questions one and two are based on the news report you have just heard
问题一和问题二基于你刚才听到的新闻报道
Question one
问题一
what may be the reason that friends are similar to each other
根据最近的研究，朋友相似的原因可能是什么
According to the recent research
根据最近的研究
question two
问题二
what does the news report say about the relationship between friends
新闻报道关于朋友之间的关系说了什么
news report two
新闻报道二
two men who have been best friends for sixty years
两位做了六十年最好的朋友的人
Have just realized they are actually brothers
刚刚发现他们实际上是兄弟
It's reported that alan robinson and walter mcdonald
据报道，艾伦·罗宾逊和沃尔特·麦克唐纳
Met in the sixth grade at a school in hawaii
在夏威夷一所学校的六年级相遇
They have been best friends ever since
从那以后一直是最好的朋友
allan was given away for adoption
艾伦出生后不久
Soon after he was born
就被送人收养
And walter never knew his father
沃尔特从未见过他的父亲
So recently they made separate attempts on dna
所以最近他们分别在DNA
Matching websites to discover more about their ancestry
匹配网站上尝试发现自己的血统
Walter was astonished to find that he matched with website user robbie seven : thirty seven
沃尔特惊讶地发现他与网站用户Robbie737匹配
He knew immediately that this was his best friend allan
他立刻知道这是他最好的朋友艾伦
Whose friends call him robbie
朋友们叫他Robbie
And flew seven thirty seven airplanes when he was a pilot
他当飞行员时驾驶七三七飞机
The pair were born to the same mother fifteen months apart
这对兄弟由同一位母亲所生，相隔十五个月
Questions three and four are based on the news report you have just heard
问题三和问题四基于你刚才听到的新闻报道
Question three
问题三
What did both alan robinson and walter mcdonald attempt to do on dna matching websites
艾伦·罗宾逊和沃尔特·麦克唐纳在DNA匹配网站上尝试做什么
question four
问题四
what did the news reports say about alan robinson and walter mcdonald
新闻报道关于艾伦·罗宾逊和沃尔特·麦克唐纳说了什么
News report three
新闻报道三
Amid all the election drama
在所有选举戏剧中
Air pollution problems and disease outbreaks
空气污染问题和疾病爆发中
Five tourists good work is being spread online
五位游客的好人好事正在网上传播
Yesterday , two male and three female tourists were spotted walking the kilometre long beach
昨天，两男三女游客被发现走在一公里长的海滩上
Picking up trash
捡垃圾
One of the male tourists from australia
其中一位男性游客来自澳大利亚
Comments said that although there was a lot of trash
评论说虽然有很多垃圾
Nobody was doing anything
但没有人做任何事情
The beach was not as nice or beautiful as it should be
海滩没有应有的那么美丽
He felt so sad to see such a gorgeous place
看到如此美丽的地方
Littered with so much trash
被这么多垃圾弄脏，他感到很难过
Thus , he and his friends decided to grab a few trash bags and clean it all up
因此，他和他的朋友们决定拿几个垃圾袋把它全部清理干净
A man passing by decided to video their good deed and put it on the internet
一位路过的男子决定拍摄他们的好人好事并放到网上
It was unclear where the rest of the group was from
不清楚团队其他成员来自哪里
But they were most likely travelling together
但他们很可能一起旅行
One local woman commented on being embarrassed that tourists were cleaning up their beach
一位当地女子评论说，游客在清理他们的海滩让她感到尴尬
Another mentioned that it was actually the natives who brought food and drinks
另一位提到，实际上是当地人带食物和饮料
Then left trash all along the island
然后把垃圾留在岛上各处
Questions five to seven are based on the news report you have just heard
问题五至问题七基于你刚才听到的新闻报道
Question five
问题五
Why did one of the male tourists feel sad
为什么其中一位男性游客感到难过
question six
问题六
Who put the good deed video on the internet
谁把好人好事的视频放到了网上
question seven why did one local woman say she was embarrassed
问题七 为什么一位当地女子说她感到尴尬
Section b directions , in this section you will hear two long conversations
B节 说明：在本节中你将听到两段长对话
At the end of each conversation
每段对话结束后
You will hear four questions
你将听到四个问题
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once
对话和问题都只读一遍
After you hear a question
听完问题后
You must choose the best answer from the four choices marked a
你必须从标有A的四个选项中选出最佳答案
B , c and d
B、C和D
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one with a single line through the center
然后在答题卡一上用横线划过相应字母
Conversation one
对话一
Hello benjamin
你好本杰明
Dan and i will be going for a run along the canal saturday morning
丹和我周六早上要沿着运河跑步
Would you like to join us
你想加入我们吗
I'd love to but i hurt my ankle
我很想去，但我伤了脚踝
Last weekend playing football with work colleagues
上周末和同事踢足球时
Oh dear , is it serious
天哪，严重吗
No , not at all
不，一点也不
I landed badly during a fall and twisted it a little
我摔倒时落地不好，稍微扭了一下
But it's no big deal
但没什么大不了的
It's just a little swollen and i should be fine for next saturday
只是有点肿，下周六应该就好了
If you still want to go for a jog
如果你还想慢跑的话
Then i won't be here next saturday
下周六我不在这里
I'm going to the zoo
我要去动物园
The zoo
动物园
Yeah
是的
My little nephew turns six and he loves the zoo
我的小侄子满六岁了，他喜欢动物园
so the whole family is going
所以全家人都去
Oh okay then i haven't been to a zoo since i was a kid
好吧，我从小就没去过动物园了
They are nowhere near as popular as they used to be when we were children
它们远不如我们小时候那么受欢迎了
I personally feel sorry for the poor animals stuck in cages
我个人为被困在笼子里的可怜动物感到难过
But there's no denying they are fun and educational for children
但不可否认，它们对孩子来说既有趣又有教育意义
Do you know if dan will be around next saturday
你知道丹下周六会在吗
Yeah , i think he will just send him a text message
是的，我想他会在，给他发个短信
He's always keen on physical activities
他总是热衷于体育活动
That's true
那是真的
Dan is extremely fits and healthy
丹非常健康
He goes to the gym most days
他大多数日子都去健身房
Plus tennis two or three times a week
加上每周打两三次网球
So what have you been doing to stay busy while you've had that swollen ankle
那么你脚踝肿着的时候一直在做什么来保持忙碌
I've been catching up on some reading
我一直在补看一些书
I was given three books over christmas
圣诞节我收到了三本书
And i'm only now getting round to reading them
我现在才开始读
Questions eight to eleven are based on the conversation you have just heard
问题八至问题十一基于你刚才听到的对话
Question eight
问题八
Why can't the man go for a run saturday morning
为什么男子周六早上不能去跑步
Question nine
问题九
why is the woman's whole family going to the zoo next saturday
为什么女子全家下周六要去动物园
question ten
问题十
what do we learn about dan from the man's description
从男子的描述中，我们了解到丹的什么
question eleven
问题十一
what has the man been doing since last weekend
男子自上周末以来一直在做什么
Conversation two
对话二
Our guest on today's book talk is john black
今天我们读书节目的嘉宾是约翰·布莱克
The author of the new best seller retire early
新书《提前退休》的作者
Thanks for having me on the show , lisa
谢谢邀请我参加节目，丽莎
John , your book is getting a lot of attention
约翰，你的书引起了很多关注
Partly because you write that most people can retire by forty
部分是因为你写道大多数人可以在四十岁退休
Is that realistic
这现实吗
Definitely
当然
When researching this book
在研究这本书时
I interviewed hundreds of people who retired by forty
我采访了数百名四十岁退休的人
Okay
好的
But how much money does a person need to retire
但一个人退休需要多少钱
I've read articles recommending one million dollars as a good figure for retirement
我读过一些文章推荐一百万美元作为退休的好数字
While most financial planners do give numbers
虽然大多数理财规划师确实给出数字
I don't think that's useful as people are living in different areas with different costs of living
但我认为这没有用，因为人们生活在生活成本不同的地区
And have different needs and wants
有不同的需求
Which is why i suggest that people aim for financial independence
这就是为什么我建议人们以财务独立为目标
What do you mean by financial independence
你说的财务独立是什么意思
Having investment income that's greater than monthly expenses
投资收入大于月支出
That sounds risky to me
对我来说这听起来有风险
What if an accident happens
如果发生事故怎么办
Or you get ill and need medical treatment
或者你生病需要治疗
Shouldn't people have extra cash for emergencies
人们不应该有额外的现金应急吗
Too many people spend their lives working on jobs they hate because they're afraid
太多人一辈子做他们讨厌的工作，因为他们害怕
So i counsel people to take risks
所以我建议人们冒险
Retirement doesn't have to be permanent
退休不一定是永久的
And if people need to
如果人们需要
They can go back to work
他们可以回去工作
But it's not always easy to get back into the workforce after an extended absence
但在长期缺席后重新进入职场并不总是容易的
True
确实
But if you keep current with your skills
但如果你保持技能更新
You will be attractive to employers
你会对雇主有吸引力
Maybe
也许
But how can anyone save enough to retire by forty
但怎么可能存够钱在四十岁退休
When most people can't retire at sixty
大多数人六十岁都退不了休
Simple . by cutting housing
很简单。削减住房
Food and transport expenses and investing half your monthly income
食物和交通开支，投资你月收入的一半
That sounds impossible
听起来不可能
I admit it's difficult
我承认这很难
But it has worked for thousands
但对成千上万的人有效
Questions twelve to fifteen are based on the conversation you have just heard
问题十二至问题十五基于你刚才听到的对话
Question twelve
问题十二
What do we learn about the man's book published recently
关于男子最近出版的书，我们了解到什么
question thirteen
问题十三
what do the articles the woman read recommend
女子读的文章推荐什么
question fourteen
问题十四
what does the man say about retirement
男子关于退休说了什么
question fifteen
问题十五
how does the man say his proposal about retirement can be carried out
男子说他的退休建议如何实现
Section c directions
C节 说明
In this section
在本节中
You will hear three passages
你将听到三篇文章
At the end of each passage
每篇文章结束后
You will hear three or four questions
你将听到三到四个问题
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once
文章和问题都只读一遍
After you hear a question
听完问题后
You must choose the best answer from the four choices marked a
你必须从标有A的四个选项中选出最佳答案
B , c , and d
B、C和D
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one
然后在答题卡一上
With a single line through the center passage
用横线划过相应字母 文章
One
一
New research from america
美国的新研究
Studies the role that the presence of individuals from different
研究了来自不同社会或种族群体的个体
Social or racial groups has in influencing consumers food choices
对消费者食物选择的影响作用
This research found college students were more likely to choose healthy food
这项研究发现，在另一个种族的观察者面前
in the presence of an observer of a different race
大学生更有可能选择健康食品
As opposed to an observer from their own race
而不是同种族的观察者
The same was true when they were with someone from a different university
当他们与来自另一所大学的人在一起时也是如此
Compared to someone from their own
与自己学校的人相比
Researchers say this was because participants anticipated more negative judgment from an outsider group
研究人员说，这是因为参与者预期来自外群体的更多负面评价
In contrast , they felt less judged by members of their own group
相反，他们感到自己群体成员的评价较少
In one experiment
在一个实验中
participants were offered the choice between candy and fruit as a snack
参与者被提供糖果和水果作为零食选择
When in the presence of an unknown student from their own university
当来自自己大学的陌生学生在场时
Only twelve percent of students selected the healthier option
只有百分之十二的学生选择了更健康的选项
However , this number was thirty one percent
然而，这个数字是百分之三十一
When in the presence of an unknown student from another university
当来自另一所大学的陌生学生在场时
Other experiments showed similar results based on racial group
其他基于种族群体的实验显示了类似结果
What's the reason for this pattern
这种模式的原因是什么
The study found that people feel judged to a larger extent by members of other groups
研究发现，人们在更大程度上感到被其他群体成员评价
Because of this , they strategically use healthy food choices to make a positive impression
因此，他们策略性地使用健康食品选择来留下好印象
There have been many attempts to help consumers make healthier choices
已经有很多尝试帮助消费者做出更健康的选择
But consumers often struggle to maintain a healthy diet
但消费者往往难以保持健康饮食
This research finds that one way to promote a healthy diet
这项研究发现，促进健康饮食的一种方法
Could be to advertise the social benefits of healthy choices
可以是宣传健康选择的社会益处
Questions sixteen to eighteen are based on the passage you have just heard
问题十六至问题十八基于你刚才听到的文章
Question sixteen
问题十六
What was the finding of the new research from america about consumers food choices
美国关于消费者食物选择的新研究发现了什么
question seventeen
问题十七
when did thirty one percent of students in the experiment select the healthier option
实验中百分之三十一的学生什么时候选择了更健康的选项
Question eighteen how could a healthy diet be promoted
问题十八 根据新研究的发现
according to the findings of the new research
如何促进健康饮食
Passage two for college students under pressure
文章二 对于压力下的大学生
A dog may be the best stress fighter around
狗可能是最好的减压方式
According to the finding of a recent study
根据最近一项研究的发现
It's a really powerful finding
这是一个非常有力的发现
Said patricia penenry , who led the study
领导这项研究的帕特里夏·佩内里说
Universities are doing a lot of great work trying to help students succeed academically
大学正在做很多伟大的工作，试图帮助学生在学业上成功
Especially those who may be at risk
特别是那些可能面临风险的学生
Due to a history of mental health issues or academic and learning issues
由于心理健康问题或学习和学术问题的历史
This study shows that traditional stress management approaches
这项研究表明，传统的压力管理方法
answers effective for this population
对这个群体有效
Compared with programs that focus on providing opportunities to interact with therapy dogs
与专注于提供与治疗犬互动机会的项目相比
The researchers measured executive functioning in the students involved in the study
研究人员测量了参与研究的学生的执行功能
Executive function is a term for the skills one needs to plan
执行功能是一个术语，指一个人需要的技能
Organize , motivate , concentrate and memorize
计划、组织、激励、集中注意力和记忆
These are skills students need to succeed in college
这些是学生在大学成功所需的技能
The researchers found that students who were most at risk
研究人员发现，风险最大的学生
Had the most improvements in executive functioning
在执行功能方面改进最大
After interacting with therapy dogs
在与治疗犬互动后
These results remained when researchers followed up six weeks later
这些结果在研究人员六周后跟进时仍然存在
Many universities provide academic stress management programs and workshops
许多大学提供学业压力管理项目和研讨会
These are traditionally very similar to college classes
这些传统上与大学课程非常相似
They often talk about ways to get more sleep
它们经常谈论获得更多睡眠的方法
Set goals , or manage stress or anxiety
设定目标，或管理压力或焦虑
Penendry acknowledges that these are really important topics
佩内里承认这些都是非常重要的话题
And these workshops help typical students succeed
这些研讨会帮助典型学生成功
But they're less helpful for struggling students
但它们对困难学生的帮助较少
Henry believes those students may experience the programs as another lecture
亨里认为这些学生可能将这些项目视为另一场讲座
And feel even more stressed
并感到更大的压力
Questions nineteen to twenty one are based on the passage you have just heard
问题十九至问题二十一基于你刚才听到的文章
Question nineteen
问题十九
what does the recent study led by patricia penenry aim to examine
帕特里夏·佩内里领导的最近研究旨在检验什么
question twenty
问题二十
what did the new study measure in the participants
新研究测量了参与者的什么
question twenty one
问题二十一
what does patricia hendry think traditional stress management programs may do
帕特里夏·亨德里认为传统压力管理项目可能会做什么
Passage three
文章三
Taking risks in business does not mean going into business blindly
在商业中冒险并不意味着盲目做生意
And then expecting great results
然后期待好的结果
On the contrary
相反
Taking risks and entrepreneurship involves careful planning and hard work
在创业中冒险涉及仔细的规划和努力工作
Nobody can really be sure
没有人能真正确定
If risks will be met with success
风险是否会带来成功
No matter how calculated they may be
无论它们多么经过计算
But this should not stop you from taking risks
但这不应该阻止你冒险
As risks are necessary if you want your business to succeed
因为如果你想让你的企业成功，风险是必要的
Some risks may not work out
有些风险可能不会成功
But an optimistic risk taker
但一个乐观的风险承担者
Will always look at failure as an opportunity to learn
总是把失败视为学习的机会
The willingness to experiment with new ideas is key to business growth
尝试新想法的意愿是业务增长的关键
As the old saying goes
俗话说
Nothing ventured , nothing gained
不入虎穴，焉得虎子
Failure will teach you how to think and plan strategically
失败会教你如何战略性地思考和计划
But just remember that not all risks are good ones
但请记住，并非所有风险都是好的
And when you fail
当你失败时
Learn from it and move forward
从中学习并继续前进
Since most people tend to avoid risk
由于大多数人倾向于避免风险
Businesses that are brave enough to take risks
足够勇敢冒险的企业
Already have a competitive advantage
已经具有竞争优势
They are the ones setting the standard with new ideas
它们是用新想法设定标准的那些
Fresh offers , and bold inventions
新鲜的产品和大胆的发明
Risk takers are best at adapting in difficult times
风险承担者最擅长在困难时期适应
Simply put , when most individuals stay away from risk
简而言之，当大多数个人远离风险时
It means less competition for risk takers
这意味着风险承担者的竞争更少
We don't know if you'll achieve what these risk takers have achieved
我们不知道你是否会实现这些风险承担者所实现的
But for as long as you want to stay safe
但只要你想要保持安全
And for as long as you are content with where your business is right now
只要你对你的企业现在的位置满意
You will never find out
你永远不会知道
Questions twenty two to twenty five are based on the passage you have just heard
问题二十二至问题二十五基于你刚才听到的文章
Question twenty two
问题二十二
what do entrepreneurs have to do when taking risks according to the passage
根据文章，创业者在冒险时必须做什么
Question twenty three what does the passage say is key to business growth
问题二十三 文章说什么是业务增长的关键
Question twenty four
问题二十四
what are we advised to do when we fail
当我们失败时，我们被建议做什么
Question twenty five
问题二十五
What does it mean to risk taking businesses
对冒险的企业来说意味着什么
when most people tend to avoid risk
当大多数人倾向于避免风险时
that's the end of listening comprehension
听力理解部分结束